Hi, my name is Rahul Kirake Pachalamakkal.
I'm a principal software engineer working
for Amazon Web Services, and today
I'm going to talk about anti-entropy
mechanisms for single-digit minute
latency in cloud security platforms.
A little bit about myself.
I've been building software for about
15 years, and within that, I've been
largely focused on building distributed
systems for various domains, ranging
from e-commerce, billing systems within
AWS, personal devices like Alexa.
And l-- for the last five years,
I've been working on vulnerability
management for AWS and now all of Amazon.
Within vulnerability management, I have
been primarily focused on architecting
and operating the security data platform.
The security data platform is responsible
for, collecting every information
that is related, that is needed for
security to be able to do detections,
assessment, and remediation of risks.
That entails ingesting information
about every security finding from every
system, learning about every asset that
can have a software vulnerability on
it, and then reasoning about all that
information at scale and providing
insights to security engineers I have--
and for the last six months, I have
also been, experimenting in transforming
software development life cycle within my
organization to be agent first So why does
security finding latency matter, right?
Cloud environments continuously surface
vulnerability findings across compute,
containers, storage, networking, and
the entire stack of the cloud, right?
A finding only has value when it reaches
to the team who can act on it fast.
If findings are delayed,
your exposure time increases.
if findings are delayed, your
incident response gets slowed
down, your detection gets slowed
down, your triage gets slowed down.
the containment of the
risk is also impacted.
a delay in findings also
leads to compliance risks.
it, especially for a company like AWS that
operates as the foundation for, several
types of businesses, it is important
for our customers to know that AWS is
compliant for, from a perspective of
security and is, and is on top of it.
And lastly, delaying findings or
delaying the finding data leads to, a
backlog of remediation that security
engineers need to manage, and that
leads to, unresolved issues, creating
more complications for security.
So minimizing the time between finding
generation and finding availability
is a critical platform requirement
for security-sensitive organizations
So, building such a distributed
platform within AWS has-- is quite
challenging, specifically for a
cloud sys-- specifically for a cloud.
a cloud spans multiple regions.
AWS operates in 40-plus regions.
the compute is distributed, the
network is distributed, and so on.
So, reasoning about it-its
security on one security data
platform imposes its own challenge.
the requirements that we need
to operate with are as follows:
We need to ensure fast delivery.
We need to ensure that no matter how
distributed the cloud is, finding needs
to reach its consumers with minimal delay.
We need to make sure that the platform,
the data platform, is highly available.
The platform needs to respond
during even failures of the cloud.
And lastly, we need to make
sure that, that there's strong
correctness within the data that
is being provided by the platform
So within a two-- so in this kind of
environment where data needs to be
delivered fast and, correctly, streaming
is the main mechanism that we use.
So from every scanner that scans for a
security finding, right when it scans
it, we've architected the data platform
in a way where events are streamed,
they get enriched, and we detect…
We have more business logic to detect,
security risks over it, and then we
vend it to the respective security
engineers or the security personnel that
deal with the remediation of the risk.
So streaming, streaming ensures that
the pipe is fast and that information
flow is as fast as it could be.
But streaming alone is not enough.
with streaming, come certain
challenges of, data loss and unlike
synchronous systems where it guarantees
cor- it guarantees correctness
within its data flow, streaming
systems have to rely on additional
mechanisms to ensure correctness
And for that, we use anti-entropy.
Anti-entropy is a distributed systems
technique that periodically compares
data across nodes, specifically
a producer and a consumer.
If data is being sent in a
synchronous, fashion, then to make
sure that the consumer got the
data that the producer produced, we
generally follow these four steps.
We compare the data sets, we check
the data sets across the producers
and the consumers to make sure
that each of them receive the data.
and if we see something is missing,
this next step is detection, and in
that we see if something is missing or
corrupted, then we try to repair it.
And once we repair it, we verify that,
okay, indeed, that the data matches
between the producers and consumers.
Within security, a vulnerability
finding that silently disappears
can be dangerous as a system outage.
So anti-entropy is the safety
net in such an environment.
So here's the architecture at a
very high level that we follow.
so it's, it's kind of two parts
in parallel within the platform.
this kind of design allows us
to optimize for speed without
sacrificing on correctness.
So as you can see, all the information
about the vulnerabilities is flowing
through as events, and then we apply
business logic on that at scale
and speed during the enrichment
process, and make sure that the data
reaches its respective destination.
Now, within these four steps, there
are multiple distributed systems,
that are managed by different teams.
And what-- That's where the second part
comes in, which is the anti-entropy.
Between each producer and consumer, we
have a pipe or a event stream that is
funneled to the reconciliation system.
The reconciliation system makes sure that,
it compares what the consumer is receiving
from every producer and what the producer
is sending, and it does this difference
detection at scale, and wherever it finds
a difference, a repair is also initiated
So naturally, in this kind of, environment
where data is flowing at such high,
high scale and volume, performance
and cost becomes a constraint.
So, we, we do-- we deal with that.
One of the primary ways we deal with that
is to minimize the computation that we
need to perform to be able to compare and
just make sure that there's no data loss.
And for that, we, primarily
rely on Merkle trees.
So when we are collecting-- when the
reconciliation system is collecting
data, we partition the data in
a specific kind of structure.
And while we are partitioning, we
also compute hashes, and that makes
the comparison really efficient.
So all we try to do is the first
level of defense is we compare
the hashes and across the producer
and consumer, and if those hashes
match, then we know that the data…
Like, we don't need to compare
the underlying data, but if
there's a mismatch, then we
go deeper and try to compare.
And this, this, reduces the cost
of computation while performing
anti-entropy for a large scale data
system so the hashing itself is done
at a attribute level, because, because
a record can exist in both systems
while containing wrong information.
So existing checks-- existence
checks alone are not enough.
As you can see in this example, system
A could have delivered a record about
a vulnerability where the severity
is critical, and system B, let's say,
received it or not received it, but
has a record with medium as a severity.
If we just match the IDs of the record,
that would, that would be insufficient.
And hence we, we compute a hash for--
hash of the object at an attribute level.
This lets us account for missing or
null fields, any kind of modified
field, like ownership or any context.
So the reconciliation layer detects not
only missing findings but also silent
corruption So once, once we detect, like,
discrepancies, then comes the repair.
And for repair, we have two techniques
that we apply or, like, two situation--
yeah, two techniques that we apply.
So the two techniques are read,
repair and hinted handoff.
So when-- whenever we see an inconsistent
version of the data, we simply re-drive
the, the data that from the producer,
to the consumer, which we have detected
is incorrect, and that, that restores
the consumer to the correct state.
And sometimes when, like, let's
say a consumer is not available,
and that also leads to, situations
where the anti-entropy sy-system
detects that data might be missing.
And in those situations, we have
created operations where, the
reconciler would wait until the
consumer system recovers, and once it
recovers, it re-drives the data that,
it needs to repair the situation.
So together, these mechanisms ensure
that infrastructure blips don't become
permanent gaps in your security data So
all in all together, it looks as follows.
Like, it combines real-time
processing with, like, the side
periodic reconciliation that runs.
So we ingest information, we enrich
it, and then we streaming it--
stream it out to our consumers.
And side by side, we are, like,
reconciling and making sure that
the data that is being vended out
is correct, and we are able to
repair it as soon as possible.
So the result is fast delivery
under normal conditions with bounded
auditable recovery when failures occur
lastly, auditability and compliance.
Like in our regulated environments,
the, like AWS, the repair
itself must be auditable.
Automated corrections without records
create their own compliance risk.
So every, every reconciliation action is
itself captured, and repairing security
data without recording the repair creates
another compliance risk by itself.
So, w- we-- the finding identifier
is we, we make sure that
the finding re-identifier is
re-restored to its original state,
if we detected inconsistency.
and then we also capture like where,
what the source of truth for that was.
We capture every repair action that was
taken, and naturally that has like it's…
We store like exactly when these events
occurred, with, with their verification
result So largely the pattern for
anti-entropy, in our cloud scale
security platform looks as follows.
Like to make sure that…
So the bottommost layer is the data source
layer, where we are sourcing the data from
multiple scanners, multiple other security
services and, application security code.
And then all of that
information is streamed.
So we have this infrastructure for
mainly streams, queues, and event buses.
And then we have the compute layer, which
takes all this information, does more
compounded detections on that information
to determine the severity of the risk,
associate ownership about the asset so
that we can reach the right resource
owner and remediate the risk at time.
And, then we also need to make sure
that this data is stored in a durable
storage and is highly available.
and on top of all of this, like the
anti-entropy and the repair system
is what gives, that correctness
touch to the entire platform.
So key takeaways are as follows.
In today's environment, your security
data platform needs to be able to deliver
and process, deliver security information
to the respective stakeholders at speed.
but with speed, it also needs, needs
to ensure correctness, and that's
where anti-entropy co- comes in.
while performing anti-entropy, it is
important to make sure that, it's cost
efficient as well as speed efficient.
And at the same time, you need to, y-
you need to preserve auditability of
the information, as well as all the
repair actions that are being taken.
high-performance security platforms should
not choose between speed and correctness.
A security-first architecture backed
by anti-entropy reconciliation
delivers fast findings and continuously
repairs the inconsistencies that
distributed systems inevitably create.
that's-- So that's my talk.
thank you everyone.